The very first thing you'll
粒子フィルターの 実装において
need to do to implement a particle filter is initialize
最初にすべきことは すべての粒子の
all your particles.
初期化です
You'll have to decide how many particles you want to use.
使用する粒子の数 を決定する必要があります
This parameter is mostly decided empirically,
ほとんどの場合 このパラメーターは 経験で決定されますが
but theoretically, the particle filter
理論的には パーティクルフィルターは
will exactly represent the Bayesian posterior distribution
パーティクル数が無限大に 近づくにつれて
as the number of particles approaches infinity.
ベイズの事後分布を 正確に表します
If you have too few particles, you
粒子が 少なすぎると
will not have enough to cover all of the high likelihood
可能性の高い位置を すべてカバーできないため
positions, so you might miss the correct position.
正しい位置を 見逃す恐れがあります
For instance, if each cell in this grid
たとえば この格子内 の各セルが同等に
is equally likely to be the car's position,
自動車の位置となる 可能性があり
and you only have three particles,
3 つの粒子しか選択 していなかったとしたら
you wouldn't have enough particles right now
自動車の位置を表すには 粒子数が不十分と
to represent this.
いえるでしょう
However, having too many particles
しかし 粒子が 多すぎても
will slow down your filter, and prevent it
フィルターの速度が低下し リアルタイムでの
from localizing a self-driving car in real time.
自動運転車のローカライゼーション が妨げられてしまいます
There are two main ways you can initialize your particles.
粒子の初期化は 大きく分けて 2 通りあります
The first is to sample uniformly across the state space.
ひとつめは、状態空間全体で 均一にサンプリングする方法です
For instance, you could divide the state space into a grid,
たとえば 常体空間を 格子状に分割し
and put one particle in each cell.
各セルに粒子をひとつずつ 配置します
However, this approach is not very practical
ただし 常体空間が広大 になる場合
if the state space is too large, such as in the case
この方法は実践的とは言えません 自動運転車のように
of a self-driving car, where the state
常体空間が 本質的に
space spans essentially the entire land
地球の全表面 地球全土にわたる場合は
surface of the earth.
この方法は実践的ではありません
The second approach for initialization
2 番目は 何らかの 初期予測で
is to sample around some kind of initial estimate.
サンプリングを 行う方法です
For a self-driving car, this initial estimate
自動運転車の場合 この初期予測は
can come from a global positioning system, or GPS.
グローバルの位置決めシステム または GPS を利用します
If you remember from the very beginning of the localization
ローカライゼーションモジュールの前半 を思い出してください
module, you cannot rely on GPS alone for localization,
GPS だけで位置を特定 することはできません
because of its low accuracy and reduced availability in certain
GPS は精度が低く 特定の環境では可用性が
environments.
低下するためです
However, GPS can be very useful to provide
ただし GPS は 位置の大まかな初期予測を
initial rough estimate of your location.
得る場合に非常に 便利です
For implementation in the particle filter project,
粒子フィルタープロジェクトで 実装する場合は
I want you to initialize your particle filter
ガウス分布からの サンプリングで
by sampling from a Gaussian distribution,
粒子フィルターを 初期化してください
Taking into account Gaussian sensor noise
初期のGPS 位置 推定および初期の進行
around the initial GPS position estimate,
方向推定の ガウスセンサーノイズ
and the initial heading estimate.
を考慮に入れ てください
Now, I want you to practice doing this in C++ by using
次は これを C++で
the C++ standard library, normal distribution function to sample
C++ 標準ライブラリを使用して 練習してみてください
positions around a GPS measurement.
GPS 観測まわりの位置のサンプリング には正規分布関数を使用します